Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Kathryn and it's the holiday season.
我是Kathryn，现在是节日季。
Today we have a lesson all about a special December holiday.
今天我们有一节课，全部关于一个特别的十二月节日。
That's right.
没错。
We are getting close to Christmas and of course today we are going to talk about Christmas
我们离圣诞节越来越近了，当然今天我们要聊聊圣诞节
in the United States and some of the typical traditions that you see over there.
在美国以及那里的一些典型传统。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to be looking at a family as they wait for Christmas morning to arrive.
所以我们要看一个家庭等待圣诞早晨到来的情景。
If you don't know what that is, don't worry, you'll hear us talk about it in a moment.
如果你不知道那是什么，别担心，一会儿你会听到我们谈论它。
But first let's listen to our dialogue.
但首先，我们来听一下对话。
What are you doing awake?
你怎么醒着？
I can't sleep.
我睡不着。
But it's almost midnight.
但都快午夜了。
Exactly.
正是。
I'm too excited for Christmas morning.
我对圣诞早晨太兴奋了。
Also, I thought I heard Santa.
还有，我好像听到圣诞老人了。
Really?
真的吗？
How do you know it was Santa?
你怎么知道是圣诞老人？
Well, I heard that naughty boys and girls get coal in their stockings so I thought I'd
嗯，我听说淘气的孩子会在袜子里得到煤块，所以我想
be nice and make Santa cookies.
表现好一点，给圣诞老人做饼干。
I even left out some milk.
我还留了一些牛奶。
I heard someone in the kitchen eating the cookies so I came downstairs.
我听到有人在厨房吃饼干，就下楼来了。
Hmm.
嗯。
Well, I know that Santa won't come down the chimney with you hiding behind the tree spying
嗯，我知道圣诞老人不会在你躲在树后偷看他的时候
on him.
从烟囱下来。
Really?
真的吗？
Really.
真的。
Let's go back upstairs and get back to bed.
我们回楼上，上床睡觉吧。
That way we can let Santa do his job.
这样我们就能让圣诞老人做他的工作了。
Then when you wake up, it will be Christmas already.
等你醒来时，就已经是圣诞节了。
Okay.
好吧。
Hey, honey, is that you?
嘿，亲爱的，是你吗？
Don't eat all the cookies.
别把饼干都吃光了。
I want some too.
我也想吃一些。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at some language on Language Takeaway.
现在让我们在“语言要点”环节看看一些语言点。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, I just said it but here's that phrase again.
好的，我刚说了，但这里再提一下这个短语。
Christmas morning.
圣诞早晨。
That's right.
没错。
So Christmas morning is December 25th in the morning, right?
所以圣诞早晨是12月25日的早晨，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Okay, so the tradition is that small children will wake up early and run downstairs and
好的，传统是小孩子会早起跑下楼，
they will find Christmas presents under the Christmas tree.
在圣诞树下找到圣诞礼物。
And so this is the Christmas morning tradition.
这就是圣诞早晨的传统。
Many countries, they celebrate Christmas on Christmas Eve, the 24th, right?
很多国家在圣诞前夜，也就是24日庆祝圣诞节，对吧？
Alright, so Christmas Eve is December 24th, Christmas Day or if it's in the morning, Christmas
好的，所以圣诞前夜是12月24日，圣诞节或如果是早晨，圣诞早晨
morning is December 25th.
是12月25日。
And as you said, kids come downstairs or go to where the Christmas tree is to look for
就像你说的，孩子们下楼或去圣诞树那里找
their presents that Santa came and left for them.
圣诞老人来给他们留下的礼物。
That's right.
没错。
So the idea, the story is that Santa comes at night, late at night and brings presents
所以这个想法，这个故事是圣诞老人晚上来，深夜来，给孩子们
for the children.
带礼物。
And when the children wake up, they see the presents but Santa has already gone.
当孩子们醒来时，他们看到礼物，但圣诞老人已经走了。
So Santa is a man, he's kind of a mythical figure with a big white beard and a red outfit
所以圣诞老人是一个男人，他有点像神话人物，有大白胡子和红色套装
and a red hat.
和红帽子。
Right.
对。
So his name is Santa Claus or just Santa.
所以他的名字是Santa Claus或简称Santa。
There are many, many different names for Santa in different cultures and different countries.
在不同文化和不同国家，圣诞老人有很多很多不同的名字。
Yeah, some people like to call him Saint Nick or Saint Nicholas but most people will call
是的，有些人喜欢叫他Saint Nick或Saint Nicholas，但大多数人会叫
him Santa in America.
他Santa，在美国。
That's right.
没错。
So this is what happens or part of what happens during Christmas Eve and Christmas Day.
所以这就是圣诞前夜和圣诞节期间发生的事或部分事。
And usually also, boys and girls will find our stockings that will be filled with candy
通常，男孩和女孩还会发现我们的袜子，里面会装满糖果
or small toys as well.
或小玩具。
That's right.
没错。
Stockings are basically socks.
袜子基本上就是袜子。
But these are special socks that you don't wear, you hang them and a lot of people like
但这些都是你不穿的特别袜子，你挂起来，很多人喜欢
to put them on the fireplace.
把它们放在壁炉上。
They hang them from the fireplace.
他们把它们挂在壁炉上。
And like you said, Marco, they're filled with sweets.
就像你说的，Marco，它们装满了糖果。
The story says that boys and girls who are nice get good things like sweets and toys
故事说，表现好的男孩和女孩会得到好东西，比如糖果和玩具，
and boys and girls who are naughty get coal.
而淘气的男孩和女孩会得到煤块。
Coal.
煤块。
So that's that black material that we use to make a barbecue for example.
就是那种我们用来做烧烤之类的黑色材料。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
It's very dirty and it's not something you want in your stocking.
它很脏，不是你想要的袜子里的东西。
Okay.
好的。
That's right.
没错。
So that's what we get in our stockings.
所以这就是我们袜子里得到的东西。
And now when the small boy and his father were talking, they were saying that he should
现在，当那个小男孩和他父亲说话时，他们说他应该
go back to bed and not hide behind the tree.
回到床上，不要躲在树后面。
So if they're in the living room or they're downstairs in the house, what tree do they
所以如果他们在客厅或楼下，他们有什么树？
have?
有？
We're not talking about a big real tree outside.
我们说的不是外面的大真树。
We're talking about the Christmas tree.
我们说的是圣诞树。
But you know, it's a long phrase, the Christmas tree.
但你知道，圣诞树是个很长的短语。
We don't have to say it that way.
我们不必那样说。
When we have a Christmas tree inside the house, we can just call it the tree.
当我们在屋里有一棵圣诞树时，我们可以直接叫它树。
Okay.
好的。
And the Christmas tree, as many of you may have seen already, is a pine tree usually
圣诞树，你们很多人可能已经见过，通常是松树，
and you put decorations on it and the presents go under it.
你会在上面挂装饰品，礼物放在下面。
That's right.
没错。
So you might hear this phrase, there are presents under the tree or there are many nice presents
所以你可能会听到这个短语：树下有礼物，或者树下有很多漂亮的礼物。
under the tree.
树下有很多漂亮的礼物。
That means there are lots of nice presents under the Christmas tree.
这意味着圣诞树下有很多漂亮的礼物。
That's right.
没错。
And well, the kid wanted to stay behind the tree and spy on Santa Claus.
嗯，那个孩子想躲在树后面偷看圣诞老人。
That's right.
没错。
So this is a verb, to spy.
所以这是一个动词，偷看。
This means to watch someone but to watch them while they don't know that you're watching
意思是观察某人，但在他们不知道你在看的情况下观察他们。
them.
观察他们。
So you're hiding but looking at someone else.
所以你躲着，但看着别人。
Right.
对。
You're spying.
你在偷看。
This is where the noun comes, a spy like James Bond.
这就是名词的来源，间谍，比如詹姆斯·邦德。
James Bond spies.
詹姆斯·邦德是间谍。
He is a very famous spy.
他是个非常著名的间谍。
That's right.
没错。
But in this case, the boy does not want Santa Claus to see him so he is spying on Santa
但在这个情况下，男孩不想让圣诞老人看到他，所以他在偷看圣诞老人。
Claus.
圣诞老人。
All right.
好的。
Very good stuff.
非常好的内容。
Let's listen to the dialogue again and review this vocab.
让我们再听一遍对话，复习这些词汇。
What are you doing awake?
你怎么还没睡？
I can't sleep.
我睡不着。
But it's almost midnight.
但都快午夜了。
Exactly.
正是。
I'm too excited for Christmas morning.
我对圣诞早晨太兴奋了。
Also, I thought I heard Santa.
而且，我好像听到了圣诞老人的声音。
Really?
真的吗？
How do you know it was Santa?
你怎么知道那是圣诞老人？
Well, I heard that naughty boys and girls get coal in their stockings.
嗯，我听说淘气的孩子袜子里会得到煤块。
So I thought I'd be nice and make Santa cookies.
所以我想表现好一点，给圣诞老人做饼干。
I even left out some milk.
我还留了一些牛奶。
I heard someone in the kitchen eating the cookies so I came downstairs.
我听到有人在厨房吃饼干，就下楼了。
Hmm.
嗯。
Well, I know that Santa won't come down the chimney with you hiding behind the tree spying
嗯，我知道如果你躲在树后面偷看圣诞老人，他就不会从烟囱下来。
on him.
偷看他。
Really?
真的吗？
Really.
真的。
Let's go back upstairs and get back to bed.
我们回楼上，回到床上吧。
That way we can let Santa do his job.
这样我们就能让圣诞老人做他的工作。
Then when you wake up, it will be Christmas already.
等你醒来时，就已经是圣诞节了。
Hey, honey, is that you?
嘿，亲爱的，是你吗？
Don't eat all the cookies.
别把饼干都吃光了。
I want some too.
我也想吃一些。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at three phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看流利度训练中的三个短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
All right.
好的。
So, Marco, there's another great phrase in here that we often use just around Christmas.
所以，马可，这里还有一个很棒的短语，我们通常在圣诞节前后使用。
What is it that Santa Claus does?
圣诞老人做什么？
Well, the way Santa Claus leaves presents for boys and girls is that he will come down
嗯，圣诞老人给孩子们送礼物时，他会从烟囱下来。
the chimney.
从烟囱下来。
We saw that when the dad said, well, Santa Claus won't come down the chimney if you're
我们看到爸爸说，如果你躲在这里树后面，圣诞老人就不会从烟囱下来。
here hiding behind the tree.
躲在这里树后面。
All right.
好的。
So the chimney is part of the fireplace.
所以烟囱是壁炉的一部分。
A fireplace is where you have a fire in your house to keep warm.
壁炉是你在屋里生火取暖的地方。
And the chimney is where the smoke goes to come outside.
烟囱是烟排到外面的地方。
But Santa Claus goes the other way.
但圣诞老人是反方向走的。
He comes down the chimney from the roof into your house.
他从屋顶顺着烟囱进到你的屋里。
That's right.
没错。
And then he leaves the presents.
然后他留下礼物。
So the father said, all right, so, you know, stop spying on Santa.
所以爸爸说，好了，你知道，别再偷看圣诞老人了。
Let's go back upstairs and get back to bed.
我们回楼上，回到床上吧。
All right.
好的。
Get back to bed.
回床上去。
And this is a phrase that you're going to hear parents say a lot to their children.
这是一个你会经常听到父母对孩子说的短语。
So if the children are awake or walking around, you say, get back to bed.
所以如果孩子醒了或者到处走动，你就说，回床上去。
That means go back to sleep.
意思是回去睡觉。
Go back to sleep.
回去睡觉。
That's right.
没错。
And we want the kid to go back to sleep so we can let Santa do his job.
我们想让孩子回去睡觉，这样我们才能让圣诞老人做他的事。
All right.
好的。
Like that last phrase, this is a phrase that you can use in other ways.
和最后一个短语一样，这个短语也可以用在其他场合。
It's not just for Christmas.
不只是圣诞节。
But we said, you know, let Santa do his job.
但我们说了，你知道，让圣诞老人做他的事。
Let Santa leave his presents.
让圣诞老人留下他的礼物。
Let's not bother Santa.
别打扰圣诞老人。
But we can change Santa with any other name.
但我们可以把圣诞老人换成任何其他名字。
Right.
对。
So you can say, I don't know, maybe your dad is working in the office and your mom will
所以你可以说，我不知道，也许你爸爸在办公室工作，你妈妈会
tell you, you know, come out here.
告诉你，你知道，出来这里。
Let dad do his job.
让爸爸做他的事。
That means don't bother dad.
意思是别打扰爸爸。
Don't distract him.
别让他分心。
Let him work.
让他工作。
Right.
对。
OK.
好的。
So that's the way that you use those phrases.
这就是使用这些短语的方式。
Very good stuff here.
这里的内容非常好。
Why don't we review one last time?
我们最后再复习一次怎么样？
What are you doing awake?
你醒着在干什么？
I can't sleep.
我睡不着。
But it's almost midnight.
但都快午夜了。
Exactly.
正是。
I'm too excited for Christmas morning.
我对圣诞早晨太兴奋了。
Also, I thought I heard Santa.
还有，我好像听到了圣诞老人。
Exactly.
正是。
How do you know it was Santa?
你怎么知道是圣诞老人？
Well, I heard that naughty boys and girls get coal in their stockings.
嗯，我听说淘气的孩子袜子里会得到煤块。
So I thought I'd be nice and make Santa cookies.
所以我想表现好点，给圣诞老人做饼干。
I even left out some milk.
我甚至还留了些牛奶。
I heard someone in the kitchen eating the cookies.
我听到有人在厨房吃饼干。
So I came downstairs.
所以我就下楼了。
Hmm.
嗯。
Well, I know that Santa won't come down the chimney with you hiding behind the tree spying
嗯，我知道如果你躲在树后面偷看圣诞老人，他是不会从烟囱下来的。
on him.
偷看他。
Really?
真的吗？
Really.
真的。
Let's go back upstairs and get back to bed.
我们回楼上，回床上去吧。
That way we can let Santa do his job.
这样我们就能让圣诞老人做他的事了。
Then when you wake up, it will be Christmas already.
等你醒来的时候，就已经是圣诞节了。
OK.
好的。
Hey, honey, is that you?
嘿，亲爱的，是你吗？
Don't eat all the cookies.
别把饼干都吃光了。
I want some, too.
我也想吃点。
All right.
好的。
So these Christmas traditions are, as we said, they're typically American, but many other
所以这些圣诞传统，就像我们说的，是典型的美国传统，但很多其他
cultures share similar traditions like this.
文化也有类似这样的传统。
That's correct.
没错。
Obviously, traditions are different in every family.
显然，每个家庭的传统都不同。
Not everyone celebrates Christmas morning.
不是每个人都庆祝圣诞早晨。
Some people celebrate Christmas Eve.
有些人庆祝圣诞前夕。
But most people will be familiar with Christmas stockings, Christmas trees, and Santa who
但大多数人都会熟悉圣诞袜、圣诞树和从烟囱下来的圣诞老人。
comes down the chimney.
从烟囱下来。
That's right.
没错。
So it also depends, I guess, on the culture and religion.
所以这也取决于，我想，文化和宗教。
Some religions celebrate Christmas differently or not at all.
有些宗教以不同的方式庆祝圣诞节，或者根本不庆祝。
So it's actually a very interesting time of the year.
所以这实际上是一年中有趣的时节。
But if you look or if you can see any American movies, like I remember this one called The
但如果你看或者能看到任何美国电影，比如我记得有一部叫《圣诞老人》的，
Santa Claus, you can see the typical American Christmas, snow and trees and presents and
你可以看到典型的美国圣诞节，雪、树、礼物和
Santa Claus, a lot of things.
圣诞老人，很多东西。
That's right.
没错。
So a good way to end this would be to say have a very Merry Christmas.
所以结束这个的好方式就是说祝你圣诞快乐。
That means have a nice holiday.
意思是祝你假期愉快。
Enjoy Christmas.
享受圣诞节。
If you're not going to celebrate Christmas for whatever reason, you can just say happy
如果你因为任何原因不庆祝圣诞节，你可以只说节日快乐。
holidays.
节日快乐。
Happy holidays.
That's right.
没错。
And of course, you can go to our website, EnglishPod.com, where we want to know if you
当然，你可以访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，我们想知道你是否
celebrate Christmas or what are the Christmas traditions in your country.
庆祝圣诞节，或者你们国家的圣诞传统是什么。
That's right.
没错。
We're very curious to hear those.
我们很好奇想听听这些。
So we'll see you soon on EnglishPod.com.
那我们很快在 EnglishPod.com 上见。
All right.
好吧。
We'll see you guys.
我们回头见。
Until then peace love and Personality Letters.
在那之前，愿和平、爱与个性信件与你同在。